Praveen Malaviya

Account Receivable

Ahmedabad, Gujarat Praveenmalaviya777@gmail.com +91 87803 25998

Expert Account receivable bringing 2.5 years of expertise in Medical Billing. Effectively manages assignment and team member. Dedicated to self-development to provide expectation-exceeding service.

Willing to relocate to: Service, MS - Gujarat - Ahmedabad, Gujarat

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 1997-11-03

Work Experience

Account Receivable

Technocruitx Universal Services Private Limited - Ahmedabad, Gujarat June 2021 to Present

- I am working on Multi-Specialty clinic.
- Under this facility claims are billed under two claim forms (CMS-1500 & CMS-1450)
- Denial Management
- Working on task which is daily allotted.

AR Executive

Shukla Information Solutions Pvt Ltd - Ahmedabad, Gujarat January 2020 to June 2021

- I was working on Dr. Specialty of Pediatric & Internal Medicine
- EV/BV Via portal & calls
- Solving clearing house rejection & payer rejection (Portal TriZetto & Change HealthCare)
- Payment and Denial Posting
- AR Follow & Denial Management
- · Verifying guidelines via insurance portal & calls taking appropriate action in timely Manner.

Sr. Customer Service Representative (CSR)

VerveMed NexGen Pvt. Ltd - Ahmedabad, Gujarat August 2017 to November 2019

- Follow up with healthcare Organization's to urgent request and update client with status and assist junior
- Handle record retrieval portal's
- Later, training new member's regarding process and make them capable to follow up with organization as "Assistant Team Leader"

Education

B.Com in Commerce

Shree Narayana Guru College - Ahmedabad, Gujarat August 2017 to October 2019

Higher Secondary in Commerce

Gujarat Higher Secondary Education Board - Ahmedabad, Gujarat June 2015 to May 2017

Skills / IT Skills

- Good listener as well as speaker
- Able to work in rotational shift as well as night shift
- Good command at Ms Excel, Ms Word & Adobe Acrobat 9.0.
- Punctual.
- Enough confident to deal with US and Canada client over the call
- Live Chat
- Cold Calling
- HIPAA
- Research
- Communication skills
- Microsoft Excel
- · Computer skills

Additional Information

Sincerely Yours,

Praveen Malaviya